

## PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Frontend development
Micro-frontends
Architecture
Backend development
Mentoring
Scrum mastering
Staring projects from scratch
Testing

### **PERSONAL SKILLS**

Reliable and professional Organized Time management Team player Fast learner Motivated

## CONTACT

P: +48 662 921 496 P: +375 29 212 0592

E: alexsharabayko@gmail.com W: alexsharabayko.github.io

City: Warsaw

## SOCIAL

fb: @alexsharabayko

inst: @alexsharabayko

github: @alexsharabayko

# ALEX SHARABAYKO

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

## **ABOUT**

Hi there! My name is Alex I have been working as frontend developer since 2013 and I'm still passionate about my job. Usually participate in big-size long-term projects but also have experience small size ones. Familiar with mentoring of teammates and scrum-mastering.

I like to do different tasks from fixing bugs and create markup to start a project and create its architecture/structure or create universal "React-to-web" components which will work with different frameworks.

I also have experience in backend: I wrote middle-size servers using Laravel, Strapi, Express. I'm especially interested in full-stack positions. Except work I like various types of activities from cooking and reading to cycling or boxing. Not a big extreme guy and not a home guy.

You are also can look at my web resume: https://alexsharabayko.github.io/

Open both remote and in-office positions. Currently in Warsaw.

Nice to meet you!

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

### JAVASCRIPT / TYPESCRIPT

Level: advanced

• Vanilla JS, Angular, Rx JS, React JS, Redux, Web Components

#### HTML/CSS

Level: advanced

• HTML5, CSS3, Sass/Scss, Styled Components

### BUNDLERS / INFRASTRUCTURE

Level: intermediate

• Webpack, Jenkins, Docker, AWS, CI/CD, Unit testing, Storybook

## **BACKAND LANGUAGES**

Level: intermediate

• Node js (Express, Strapi), PHP (Laravel), Python

## MOBILE DEVELOPMENT

Level: intermediate

React Native, Ionic, adaptive/responsive markups



## PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Frontend development
Micro-frontends
Architecture
Backend development
Mentoring
Scrum mastering
Staring projects from scratch
Testing

## PERSONAL SKILLS

Reliable and professional Organized Time management Team player Fast learner Motivated

#### CONTACT

P: +48 662 921 496 P: +375 29 212 0592 E: alexsharabayko@gmail.com W: alexsharabayko.github.io City: Warsaw

## SOCIAL

fb: @alexsharabayko

inst: @alexsharabayko

github: @alexsharabayko

# ALEX SHARABAYKO

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### LEAD FRONTEND DEVELOPER

IDT Corporation | May 2019 - Current

Tech stack: Angular, React, Web Components, Jenkins, Docker, Sip JS, HTML/SCSS, WebRTC, Redux, Rx JS. Webpack, Node JS

Working as a frontend tech lead and a scrum master on net2phone - a VOIP solution for small/medium size companies.

- Implementation of "micro-frontend"
- Started common UI library of components which can work with any framework
- Started projects from scratch
- Feature implementations
- Bug fixing
- Team mentoring
- Scrum mastering
- Working on non-standard tech task like SIP issues, WebRTC or addon for Google Calendar

## FRONTEND / BACKEND DEVELOPER, CO-FOUNDER

Oh What App | Mar 2020 - Mar 2021

Tech stack: React Native, Strapi, Node JS, Postgres, Firebase

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ohsmmmobile My friends and I were trying to create our own sophisticated app for SMM in Instagram. Minimal goal for me - learning a backend development.

- Participated in frontend development on React Native
- Created the server for this app using Strapi CMS
- Features / UX discussions

## FRONTEND / BACKEND DEVELOPER, CO-FOUNDER

Healthgoing | Mar 2020 - Current

Tech stack: Angular, RxJS, HTML/Tailwind, Laravel, Stripe, WebRTC, Web sockets, Node JS  $\,$ 

https://healthgoing.com/

My friends and I are trying to create solution to connect nutritionists with their customers

- Started and participated in frontend development on Angular
- Created the server for this app using Laravel framework for PHP
- Features / UX discussions

## SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Exp Capital | Aug 2018 - May 2019

Tech stack: Angular, Ionic

Participated in development of https://capital.com/ and https://currency.com/ as a senior frontend dev.

- Participated in frontend development with Angular and Ionic
- Bug fixing



## PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Frontend development
Micro-frontends
Architecture
Backend development
Mentoring
Scrum mastering
Staring projects from scratch
Testing

## **PERSONAL SKILLS**

Reliable and professional Organized Time management Team player Fast learner Motivated

#### CONTACT

P: +48 662 921 496 P: +375 29 212 0592

E: alexsharabayko@gmail.com W: alexsharabayko.github.io

City: Warsaw

#### SOCIAL

fb: @alexsharabayko

inst: @alexsharabayko

github: @alexsharabayko

# ALEX SHARABAYKO

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

MIDDLE / SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Viaden Media / Skywind | Sept 2014 - Jul 2018

Tech stack: Angular, React JS,HTML/CSS/SASS, Angular, Node JS, Electron, Backbone JS, jQuery,

Started as a middle frontend developer. At first helped my team to develop https://www.galabingo.com/ and https://www.galacasino.com/ - fixed bugs, implementing new features on Backbone.

Then participated in development of internal Backoffice using angular and started Electron app from scratch for our customers.

- Participated in frontend development using Backbone, Angular, React
- Bug fixing
- Started Electron / Angular desktop app from scratch
- Feature implementations
- Bug fixing
- Team mentoring

### JUNIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

HiQo Solutions | Jul 2013 - Aug 2014 Tech stack: JS, HTML/CSS, jQuery, Backbone

Starting point of my career. Was member of internship program then worked as junior engineer: fixed bugs, implemented small features for different projects, for example https://www.hiqo-solutions.com

- Participated in frontend development on vanilla JS, jQuery
- Bugs fixing
- Small features implementations

### **EDUCATION**

BACHELOR DEGREE - MATH FACULTY

Belarusian State University | 2010 - 2015

THE COMPLETE NODE. JS DEVELOPER COURSE
PYTHON AND DJANGO FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER BOOTCAMP
BUILD A BACKEND REST API WITH PYTHON & DJANGO

Udemy